鸡奸案 小姐
Nice bit of buggery, Miss.
暴露狂 先生
Bit of flashing, sir.
我的是什么？
What is it?
- 强奸案 先生 - 好案子
- Rape, sir. - Very good rape.
- 太好了 - 小姐 你的也是强奸案
- Great. - Miss. Another good rape.
两个都是好案子 新鲜出炉的
Very good rapes, the pair of them. All singing, all dancing.
审判都要持续一周 二位工作愉快
Both will run for a week. Enjoy.
- 保姆爱你们 - 你说什么？
- Nanny Loves You. - What?
"保姆爱你们" 全约克郡最顶级的保姆中介
"Nanny loves you." The best suppliers of class nannies in the whole of Yorkshire.
今晚他们会派保姆过去帮你们照顾孩子
Tonight they're sending round the answer to your child care problems.
- 好让我们把精力花在案子上 - 我多为你们着想
- So we can go on with our very good rapes. - I do look after you.
Black小姐 你的是审讯
Miss Black. Trial, Miss.
刑事法庭？
Crown Court?
是的 小姐 有个家伙殴打了一个妓女
Yes, Miss. Some bloke beating up a prostitute.
- 什么案子都跟性脱不了关系 - 这个世界不会好了
- Sex, sex, sex. - It's a bad old world.
摘要慢慢看 别着急 读仔细点
No rush when you read it. Just take your time, and read it properly.
一夜的时间比你想象的要长
A night is longer than you think.
但如果你静不下心 一夜时间也会过得很快
But if you panic, it gets shorter.
有事给我打电话
Ring me if you need me.
无论如何 不论怎么样
Under no circumstances whatsoever, ever,
我们的这位体坛偶像绝对不能承认这起猥亵罪
does our sporting hero plead to this indecent assault.
- 无罪辩护 帮他洗脱罪名 - 认不认罪我会根据案子实际情况决定
- Get him to fight it. Be brilliant, get him off. - I'll judge the case on its merits.
我不会去顾及媒体对审讯的大规模报导能给我们带来多大利益
I will have no regard for the benefits of the massive publicity a trial would attract
我也不会让你的叽叽喳喳影响我的判断
and I'm deaf to the desperate noises being made by my senior clerk.
好孩子
Good boy.
不错 做得好
Good job. Well done.
新装潢 我喜欢墙面的黄绿色
The new decor. I love a bit of avocado.
你知道自己的问题吗 Stevie？
You know the thing about you, Stevie?
你能让男人神魂颠倒
You can take a man's breath away.
你平时见大客户时就穿这样？
Is this how you usually dress to meet a big new client?
我希望客户不要感到拘谨 穿着舒适的宽松裤 身旁还有棕色小狗作伴
I like clients to be at their ease. Nice pair of slacks, beige Puppies.
- Val的惯用伎俩 - 哪个Val？
- The Val technique. - Val?
- 跟着一起唱 - 你说什么？
- Sing-along-a. - What?
Doonican
Doonican.
Val Doonican，爱尔兰歌手，曾主持过BBC电视节目The Val Doonican Show
- 小狗是干嘛的？ - 嘘 别说话
- Puppies? - Hush.
二台的广播节目"The Shoes They Wear"
The Shoes They Wear on Radio2.
他会认罪
He's pleading.
- 不认 - 要认
- No. - Yes.
- 我刚才那是陈述句 不是疑问句 他必须认罪 - 为什么？
- That was a statement, not a question. He's pleading. - Because?
因为他当着四万名球迷的面把自己的舌头伸进了原告的喉咙
Because 40,000 people witnessed him stick his tongue half way down the throat to the right back.
猥亵罪 明摆着的 没有可辩之处
Indecent assault. Open and shut. No defence.
所以说认罪的决定不是他自己做的
So he hasn't told you he's pleading guilty though?
是我跟他说要认罪
I've told him.
- 你没事吧？ - 什么？
- You all right? - What?
- 没事 - 你声音都高八度了
- Fine. - Your voice goes up an octave.
什么？
What?
- 我的审讯 - 不会有事的 有我罩着你
- My trial. - It'll be all right. I'll look after you.
如果我输了 就完了
If I go down... End.
律师这条路就走到头了
No more horsehair on head. Ever.
我说过 我会摆平
I told you. I'll look after you.
我想好了 你去试试
I've decided. Go for it.
申请皇家律师
Apply for silk.
- 怎么了？ - 没什么
- What's up? - Nothing.
少来 肯定有事 你最近总是看窗户外面
No, not nothing. You're looking out the window a lot.
这种事我懂 没事才怪
I know about looking out windows. Bollocks, nothing.
我做律师做得很成功 是不是？
I've got a very good practice, haven't I?
不然我也不会让你申请皇家律师
Which is why you should apply for silk.
我比其他同龄的律师都要出色
My practice is better than any of my contemporaries'.
如果申请成功 你将会是英国最年轻的QC
You'd be the youngest QC in England if you get it.
QC，Queen's Counsel，英国王室法律顾问，皇家律师
如果办公室主任的名字后面有QC两个字做后缀 对我们事务所的发展大有好处
And it would make a difference, having those magic letters after our Head of Chambers.
不要再看窗户了 摆脱
Now fuck off with this window shit, can you?
哦 对了 小姐 有件事我得搞清楚
Oh, by the way, Miss. One thing I need to know.
你没有什么丑闻吧？ 有的话你最好告诉我
Any skeletons? Best you tell me if there are.
瞧啊 这才是我想看到的
Look at that. That's what I like to see.
最炙手可热的案子出现在我们事务所的等候室 再好不过了
Page-one crime in my waiting room. Love it.
- 那人谁啊？ - "谁？" 你居然不知道他是谁
- Who's that? - "Who's that?" Who's that!
你是穿越来的 还是在装清高？
Are you dead, sir, or just practising for when you're a judge?
- 他是Stuart Pound，Tom - 哦 就是他啊
- Stuart Pound, Tom. - Oh, terrific.
加斯科因是谁？ 什么叫T恤？
Who's Gazza? What's a T-shirt?
保罗·加斯科因（Paul Gascoigne），前英格兰国家队中场
在我活着的那个时代 同性恋就是快乐的代名词
In my day, "gay" meant "happy."
- Stevie跟我说了 - 是吗 她都说什么了？
- Stevie's told me. - Has she? What?
她说我必须认罪
That I've got to plead guilty.
认罪能让纷争降到最低
It has the advantage of... minimising the fuss.
纷争？
Fuss?
不能再有更多的不良影响了 我担不起
I can't afford for this to get any more damaging.
认罪的话 媒体就不会没完没了的大规模报道 这事慢慢就能过去了
This way, I can avoid the press crawling over me for days and days and be done with it.
审讯会给Stuart和他的职业生涯抹黑
A trial would be bad for Stuart and his profile.
- 如果我认罪 你可以跟法官说 - 说什么？
- If I plead guilty, you can tell the judge... - What?
就说这只是个低级玩笑 我对此感到很抱歉 之类之类的
...that it was a tasteless joke and how sorry I am and all that.
我就问你一个问题 你觉得自己有罪吗？
I'm gonna ask you one question. Do you feel guilty?
- 好极了 - 什么好极了？
- Excellent. - Excellent?
- 我知道答案了 - 什么答案？
- Well, I have my answer. - What answer?
- 我都没有回答 - 是啊 你是没回答 沉默说明了一切
- I didn't... - No, you didn't, which tells me everything.
律师当了这么多年 总能分清哪种是愧疚的沉默 哪种是无辜的沉默
There's one thing you know from the life of the bar is the difference between guilty silence and innocent silence.
- 听我说 - 不用 你的话说完了
- Look... - No, please. You've done your bit.
意思表达的很清楚 后面的交给我
You've expressed yourself. The rest is me.
对方的后卫Biggs全场都在防守你的进攻
For 89 minutes, their full-back, Biggs, has been kicking you.
然而比赛结束前最后一刻 奇迹发生了
And then it happens. Last minute.
在你脚尖触到球的那一刹那 也许再早一点 人们就看清了球的走向
From the moment you hit it, maybe even before, we can see where it's going.
球门右上角 全场寂静一片
Top corner. Silence.
接下来球迷一阵欢呼
Then cacophony.
你们赢了 Biggs前面整整89分钟的防守功亏一篑
And the game is won and Kicking Boy's 89 minutes of kicking you means nothing.
你做了什么 我来告诉你
And what do you do? I'll tell you.
你挣脱了狂欢的队友 走向了对方后卫Biggs
You shrug off jubilant team-mates and head for Kicking Boy.
观众席上嘘声一片
The crowd exhale.
球迷们恨你 他们对你由爱转恨
And they hate you. Their love has turned to hate.
但他们恨你是因为他们不明白你为什么要这么做
But they hate you because they don't understand. They've missed it, the whole point.
为什么会做出如此惊人的、清晰的举动
Your exquisite, articulate act.
- 球迷没明白什么 Alex？ - 讽刺 这个吻代表讽刺
- What did they miss, Alex? - Irony. It's an ironic kiss.
讽刺并不猥琐 讽刺不算冒犯
Irony isn't indecent. Irony is not an assault.
- 这就是你的辩词 - 太有才了
- That's your defence. - Brilliant.
你有什么需要补充的吗？
Is there anything you want to say?
太棒了 我甚至都不用认罪 而且这样一来
Brilliant. I don't have to plead guilty, and this way...
审讯会赢得干净利落
It's a nice, clean trial.
无罪辩护 Stuart 一路顺利赢下辩护 不要考虑什么认罪 认罪已经成历史了
Not guilty, Stuart. Straight down the line. Forget pleading. This is history.
没人能跟历史过不去
And you don't fuck with history.
"审讯赢得干净利落" Alex 我就问一个问题 那个吻到底是不是讽刺意味的？
"Nice, clean trial," Alex. Single issue - was the kiss ironic?
被跟我绕弯 这种案子弯是绕不过去的
No mud-slinging. Cos mud comes back in cases like this.
而你要完完全全的代表客户 这就意味着不能让他牵扯进
And you have to represent the whole client, which means keeping him away
性丑闻 性取向 以及乱写一通的娱乐小报
from sex, sexuality and all that grubby tabloid kind of stuff.
没错
Precisely.
我能怎么说 [这段话实在不知道他在讲啥]
What can I say? There's a jolly neat crease in front of my slacks, I'm softly lit,
[大家就自行脑补吧 我真的尽力了]
my mum knitted my pullie, I look great on a stool and I'm so clean, my teeth squeak.
- 你跟Val有共同点 - 我一直跟你怎么说来着
- There is a resemblance. You and Val. - That's what I've been telling you.
你好 亲爱的
Hello, darling.
嗨
Hi.
你当保姆多长时间了？
How long have you been a nanny?
- 三年了 - 好的
- Three years now. - Right.
你好啊
Hello.
小丹丹 丹尼
Little Dan. Little Danny.
小丹尼
Danny boy.
我去那啥... 拿一下奶瓶
I'm just gonna... get his bottle.
我去帮忙
I'll give you a hand.
她看着挺靠谱的
She seems pretty together.
- 我不喜欢她喊他小名 - 怎么了？ - 丹 丹尼 小丹尼
- I don't like the way she shortens his name. - What? - Dan. Danny. Danny boy.
- 总是这么叫他 - 这你也有意见？
- Saying it all the time. - What are you on about?
他俩才刚见面 她也熟络的太快了吧
Well, she's only just met him. It's a bit over-familiar about American.
他才六个月大 我觉得他不会想
"我去 她即没经验 又爱叫我小名" 你认为呢 Billy？
He's six weeks old. I don't suppose he's thinking,
"Bugger me, she's a bit fresh, she's a bit heavy on the name usage." Do you, Billy?
可不好说 儿子那么聪明
He's a brilliant baby.
- 到底怎么回事 Billy - 我也说不清
- What is it, Billy? - I don't know.
试着说清
Try.
- 她有点... - 什么？
- She's a bit... - Yeah?
- 你懂的 - 我不懂
- You know. - No.
- 有点胖 - 什么 天哪 Billy
- Fat. - What... Jesus, Billy!
我也不想 但是现在是在找人照顾我们的宝宝
I'm sorry, but I think you need to be honest about these things
这种问题必须要考虑
when it comes to who's gonna look after your baby.
- 胖跟照顾宝宝有什么关系 - 遇到紧急情况她可能跑不动
- What the hell does that have to do with it? - She might need to run.
- 我懒得跟你说这个 - 我觉得她胖是因为活得不开心 我觉得她不幸福
- I'm not gonna talk to you about this. - I think she's unhappy-fat. I think she's not happy.
从她的眼神能看出来 当你有时遇到那种特别悲惨的当事人的时候
It's in her eyes. You know that look you sometimes get with clients
- 你也能从他们的眼神中看出来同样的忧伤 - 先回去吧
- of voracious sadness? - Let's go back in.
在你照顾孩子时候 有过什么意外经历吗？
Have you ever had any accidents with children in your care?
- 是的 - 说说看
- Yes. - Right.
当时我照看的一个两岁小孩从公交车上摔下去了
A two-year-old I looked after fell off a bus.
不是直接从车上掉下去 只不过从台阶摔倒路上了 而且当时公交车是静止状态
Not right off. Just from the step onto the road. And the bus was stopped.
那个孩子也叫Daniel
He was called Daniel, too.
你当时采取了什么措施？
What did you do?
我先止了血 然后带他去了急诊室
I stemmed the bleeding and I took him to Casualty.
- 怎么去的？ - 坐公交
- How? - By bus.
好吧
Right.
幸好公交上有一个好心人
Luckily, there was a nice man on the bus.
幸好？
Luckily?
他替我照看了另一个四岁的孩子
He looked after the four-year-old for me.
- 在急诊室？ - 在公交站台
- At Casualty? - At the bus stop.
我接受过很多急救培训
I've had a lot of first-aid training.
很好
Good.
孩子的食物呢？ 你对食物怎么看？
What about food? Er... what are your thoughts on food?
再见
Bye.
哦 这一点都不好笑
Oh, it's completely not funny.
现在该怎么办
What we gonna do?
- 你可以把你的强奸案推掉 - 或者你把你的推掉
- You could return your rape. - You could return your rape.
我管你什么时间 你居然派了一个精神有问题的胖子过去
I don't care what time it is. You sent them a fat psychopath.
你们这算是哪门子的保姆中介啊
What kind of nanny agency are you?
不 你给我听着 明晚你给我找个保姆过去 不要胖子
No. Listen. I want someone round there tomorrow night who is not fat.
我要瘦的 而且要个精神正常的 老子手上有两个大的强奸案
I want thin and I want normal. I got two massive rapes
能不能赢就指望你们中介了！
depending on Nanny Fucking Loves Ya!
- 喂？ - Bob 明天你不用来事务所了
- Hello? - Bob. Tomorrow, don't come to chambers.
你去当奶爸
You're baby-sitting.
你觉得让Bob照顾Daniel没问题吗
D'you think it will be all right Bob with Daniel?
- 不觉得 你呢 - 我也不觉得
- No. Do you? - No.
- 你的案子是... - 有罪辩护？ 我觉得应该是 你呢？
- Are you er... - Pleading? I thought I might. You?
- 我想也是 - 我的被告纯粹是个人渣
- I thought I might. - Pure scum, my bloke.
- 我的客户也是人渣 - 我爱你
- Mine too, pure scum. - I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
- 我不确定 - 什么？
- I'm floating. - What?
- 上面写着我的审讯不确定 - 好的
- It says here I'm floating. - Right.
- 什么叫"不确定"？ - 就是说你的案子是候补
- What's "floating"? - It means your trial's a back-up case.
- 目前还没安排你上庭 等某间审判庭空出来了 才轮到你上
- Haven't got you on court. But one becomes free, you go in to it.
意味着你会去我的审判庭 因为我是有罪辩护
Which will be mine, cos I'm pleading.
- 我是替补 - 对
- A substitute. - Yeah.
- 那我就有更多时间做准备了 - 昨晚慌了？
- So I've got more time to prepare. - Night got short on you?
你不是Stone那个案子的主辩护律师吧 Rose
You're not leading Stone, are you, Rose?
不是 这位是Morag 给Stone辩护的是她
No. This is Morag. She's doing it.
以我的资历是不会接人身伤害这种小案子的
Knockabout ABHs are a bit beneath a woman of my experience.
等你准备好了过来见我
Come and find me when you're ready.
他就是个不入流的小文员
Sad old hack.
Guy
Guy.
这位是Morag
This is Morag.
请John...
Will John...
... Stone到大厅来一趟 谢谢
...Stone please come to the lobby? Thank you.
你应该有罪辩护
You should be pleading.
被告一眼就被指认 而且以我从业二十年经验来看
Very clear ID evidence, with the best descriptions in those sort of circumstances
这案件性质在同类案件中算是最乐观的
I've seen in my 20 years at the bar.
指认的还是个吸毒的妓女 简直再好不过
And from a junkie whore, it's fantastic.
你再好好考虑清楚吧 你叫什么来着
Well, think about it... I've forgotten your name.
- 我叫Morag - 哦 对 Rose告诉过我
- Morag. - Oh, yes. Rose said.
我跟Rose是老交情了
Rose and I go way back.
她最擅长的就是拿我开涮
She's got teasing me down to a fine art.
她说你是个不入流的小文员
She said you're a sad old hack.
你可以从出庭律师肩上的"残渣"
You can judge the size of a barrister's practice
判断他的优劣
by the amount of debris on the shoulders.
- 什么残渣？ - 头皮屑
- Debris? - Dandruff.
头屑越多 说明这个律师越不行
The more there is, the poorer the practice.
我叫Guy Beethoven 我是排期员 你是我排的唯一一个候补 Black小姐
Guy Beethoven. List officer. You're my only floater, Miss Black.
- 你怎么知道我叫什么 - 我什么都知道
- How d'you know my name? - I know everything.
你今年二十二岁 土生土长的苏格兰人
You're 22. Deeply, deeply Scottish.
而且这会儿你感到有点紧张
And right at this moment, a little bit scared.
别怕 没问题的
Don't be. You'll be fine.
- 你怎么知道会没问题？ - Rose Fitzgerald说的话从来都对
- How do you know? - Rose Fitzgerald is never wrong.
所以如果在上庭之前她跟我说
Which also means that when she tells me she needs hours and hours
她需要很长时间与当事人沟通 我也愿意相信她
to talk to her client before going into court, I'm very happy to believe her.
别着急 等你准备好了 我就安排你上庭
Take your time, and when you're ready, we'll put you on.
- 太恶心了 - 他的舌头在哪？
- It was disgusting. - And where was his tongue?
就在我嘴里
His tongue was in my mouth.
- 多久？ - 很久
- For how long? - A long time.
好吧 就几秒钟 但对我而言度秒如年
Well, a few seconds. It seemed like ages.
你当时作何感受？
And how did that make you feel?
我感觉像是被强奸了一样
I felt raped.
假设Stuart Pound企图在你家的客厅强吻你
If Stuart Pound had tried to kiss you and it was in your own front room,
- 你会怎么做？ - 我会把他推开
- what would you have done? - I would've shoved him off.
- 你会暴跳如雷 - 是的 我会
- You'd have gone berserk. - Yeah, I would of.
- 你可能会打他 - 肯定要揍他一顿
- You might have hit him. - I would've clocked him one, definitely.
Stuart Pound的球技能甩你好几条街 是不是？
Stuart Pound is a much better footballer than you, isn't he?
我是后卫 我们分工不同
I'm a defender. There are different facets.
但是你梦寐以求 能像他那样冲锋陷阵
Those things he does you can only dream about.
前锋和后卫不一样 防守本身也是一门艺术
It's different. Defending's an art in itself.
在英国可不是
Not in this country, it isn't.
在这场比赛中 你负责防守Pound
In this game, it was your job to sit on Pound,
化解他在你方球门周围造成的进攻威胁
to nullify the risk he poses.
是
Yeah.
也是他的进攻与你的防守之间的一场个人较量
A private battle. His art versus yours.
- 而你却输了 - 呃...
- And you lost. - Well...
你没能阻止他进球得分赢得比赛 这让你觉得自己像个傻冒
He scored the goal that won the game and you didn't stop him. It made you look like the donkey you are.
法官大人 我认为这是无谓的人身攻击
I don't think personal abuse is called for, Your Honour.
"傻冒"在阿森纳球员之间可是一种昵称
"Donkey" is a term of endearment at Arsenal.
他让你颜面扫地 而像你这么一个
Leaving you for dead, as he did, a man like you -
满腔热诚的足球队员 这简直是一种耻辱
dedicated, passionate about your work - it was a humiliation.
没有哪个后卫会希望发生这种事
No defender likes being done like that.
- 哪种事？ 被羞辱？ - 对 可以这么说
- "Done"? Humiliated? - Yeah, I accept that.
恳请法官大人给我一点时间 我有个问题需要向事务律师咨询
Would Your Honour give me a moment. There's something I need to consult my solicitor about.
- 你看上去美翻了 - 你疯了
- You're looking incredibly gorgeous. - You're mad.
我迫不及待想要体验你的美
And bad and dangerous to know.
他试图强吻你时 你有把他推开吗
Did you shove him off when he tried to kiss you?
没有
No.
- 你有暴跳如雷吗？ - 没有
- Did you go berserk? - No.
- 你有揍他吗？ - 没有
- Did you clock him one? - No.
就是说你什么都没做？ 因为这个吻对你不构成任何威胁
You didn't do anything at all? Because this kiss was no threat to you.
你输掉比赛已经够羞辱了 这个吻只是对此作了一个注释 留个记号
You were already humiliated. The kiss was a comment on your humiliation. A remark.
我没听懂你的意思
I don't follow you.
你今天之所以站在这里 是因为Stuart Pound让你出了丑
You're here today because Stuart Pound made you look a fool.
是的
Yeah.
在赛场上 而不是强吻事件
With a football. Not with his tongue.
- 很好 - 什么很好？
- Good. - Good?
我原本以为你会是个下流老男人 你知道的
I thought you might be a scummy old thing. You know.
肮脏 虚伪 那种人 你懂的
Musty. Cheesy. The type who... You know.
- 但你不是 - 懂了
- But you're not. - Right.
- 这是你第一次？ - 上刑事法庭吗？ 是的
- Your first time? - Here? Yes.
第一次嫖妓？
Your first time with a prostitute?
听着 你只需要知道 她被打了 但打她的不是我 这就够了
Look, all you need to know is she was assaulted, but it wasn't me.
- 她从一排人中把你认出来了 - 她认错人了
- She picked you out in an ID parade. - She got it wrong.
事实上 这种事是很常见的
Actually, it's er, very common.
律师的专业术语叫做 真实性误信
Genuine but mistaken belief, as the er... lawyers call it.
等你以后有了经验 就知道了
You'll find that, as you get more experienced.
- 那是 - 是她
- That's... - That's her.
看上去你们刚才像是在... 你们认识吗？
It looked as if just now... Do you two know each other?
这个... 是的 认识
Well... y-yes, we do.
我是她的常客
I'm a regular of hers.
这点很重要 这说明她能把你从一排人中选出来 是因为她认识你
That's great. It means she picked you out in the ID parade because she knows you
而不是因为是你殴打的她
and not because you were the man who attacked her.
我想走到他身边 拍拍他的背之类的
I tried to get to him, you know, to pat him on the back or whatever.
- 庆祝我们的胜利 - 然后呢？
- To celebrate, like. - And?
他对庆祝胜利没兴趣 他挣开我们
He wasn't interested. Kind of shrugged us off.
"我们"指的是你 还是你们球队的所有成员？
"Us" meaning you or "us" meaning members of your team collectively?
- 啥？ - 算了 当我没问
- What? - Oh, forget I spoke.
- Stuart只想到他那边去 - 哪个"他"？
- Stuart just wanted to get to him. - "Him"?
Biggsy 对方的右后卫
Biggsy. Their right-back.
当Stuart Pound走近Biggs的时候 你能看到他的脸吗？
And could you see Stuart Pound's face as he was approaching Biggs?
- 是的 当然能 - 当时他脸上是什么表情？
- Yeah, absolutely. - What was the expression on his face?
是 呃 火冒三丈
It was er... It was a smoulder.
做给我们看看
Show us.
- 什么？ - 做那个表情给我们看看
- Sorry? - Show us the smoulder.
- 什么意思？ - 做来看看
- What d'you mean? - Do it.
- 我吗？ - 就是你
- Me? - You.
- Stuart Pound当时就是这个表情？ - 是的 没错
- Is that what Stuart Pound did? - Yeah. Absolutely.
- 像是一股沉默的怒火 - 我想是的
- A sort of... pantomime smoulder. - I suppose.
- 你常去剧院看戏吗？ - 不去
- Do you go to the theatre? - No.
- 不像是个中后卫该去的地方？ - 对 不是
- Not a big centre-half thing to do? - No, not really.
你可能会觉得看戏有点娘娘腔
You'd probably say it was a bit poncey.
- 有点吧 - 就像Stuart Pound
- A bit. - Like Stuart Pound.
你对Stuart Pound怎么看？
What are your feelings about Stuart Pound?
嗯... 我并不想站在这里出庭作证 他是我的队友
Well... I don't really want to be here. He's a team-mate.
对我来说并不容易
It's not easy for me.
- Stuart Pound去剧院吗？ - 是的
- Does Stuart Pound go to the theatre? - Yeah.
你对此有什么想法吗？
How do you feel about that?
- 没有 - 没有？
- Nothing. - Nothing?
那大家在更衣室里都怎么议论他？
Well, what's the dressing-room line on it?
哦 拜托 更衣室里总是会有善意的玩笑
Oh, come on. Every dressing room is full of good old, rib-digging mickey-taking.
人人都爱开玩笑 而且大家都心领神会
It's what you do. And everyone gets it.
是这样没错
I suppose.
那你们都是这么揶揄Stuart Pound的？
So how does it go with Stuart Pound?
呃 就是说他做事娘娘腔啊之类的
Well, erm, you know, it's to do with him doing the poncey stuff.
足球运动员怎么称呼同性恋？
What's the footballers' word for homosexual?
同志
Gay.
请您实话实说 Hurd先生
Can I remind you that you're on oath, Mr Hurd?
鸭子？
Ponce?
玻璃？
Nonce?
基佬？  娘炮？
Queer? Woofter?
你刚才是在笑吗？
Do I see a smile?
现在休庭
I think we'll adjourn now.
- 这下好了 好极了 - 就是 那帮陪审团太讨厌了
- Great. Just great. - I know. The jury, they stink.
玻璃 娘炮 基佬 你发现没有
Ponce. Woofter. Queer. Did you see?
他每用一个词 所有陪审员都会不约而同的在座位上动一下
Each time he hit him with one of those, they shifted in their seats, all twelve, simultaneously.
这动作根本就是有成见的表现
If prejudice were a gesture, it would be the shifting of English buttocks.
- 这一切都是由你引起的 - 什么？
- And you started it. - What?
娘炮和剧院 是你先提的 是你让控方律师有机可乘 是你让他们针对他
"Poncey" and "theatre". That was you. You let the prosecution in. You let them get to him.
你答应过审判会赢得干净利落 你没做到
You promised him a good, clean trial. You said. That was a lie.
- 准备好了吗？ - 好了
- Are you ready? - Yes.
我的被告已经做好认罪准备了 午饭过后你就会站在我即将结束辩护的法庭上
Then consider my man ready to plead. You'll be in my court ten minutes after lunch.
谢谢你 Rose
Thanks, Rose.
我打算申请皇家律师
I'm applying for silk.
我知道 我听说了
I know. Word gets round.
你想让我给你写推荐信
And you want me to write a reference.
我会在信中写道 你是一名优秀的律师
And in it I'll put that you're a brilliant advocate
而且有着我见过的最美丽的双唇
with the most beautiful mouth I've ever seen.
- 我不想要你的推荐信 - 为什么？
- I don't want a reference from you. - Why not?
因为我希望直接了当 我希望仅凭自己的实力来申请
Because I want it done straight. I want my application determined on its merits, and only on its merits.
你觉得我会公私不分？
And you don't think I'm capable of keeping the professional and the personal separate?
我想让这件事正大光明的进行
It's the way I want it done. Above board.
- 老实说我觉得有点羞辱 - 别这么想
- I feel a bit insulted, to be honest. - Don't be.
- 给我一个愤怒的表情 - 什么？
- Do me a smoulder. - Pardon?
我想请你 De Souza小姐
I'm asking you, Miss de Souza,
为我做一个怒火中烧的表情
to smoulder for me.
我从来不怒火中烧
I don't do smoulders.
那就给我一个夸张的吻
Then kiss me indecently.
这个可以有
That... I do.
- 谢谢你 De Souza小姐 - 不客气 法官大人
- Thank you, Miss de Souza. - It's a pleasure, Your Honour.
今天下午我休息 不用坐庭
I've got the afternoon off. We're not sitting.
是吗
Really?
是的
Really.
- 明天 - 嗯
- Tomorrow. - Yes.
他们是不是会用你刚才那招反过来对付我
Will they do to me what you did to him?
他们会想尽办法
They'll try.
- 都是因为你才会这样 - 什么？
- Because that's what you've made this. - What?
现在这种我最不希望看到的局面 是你造成的
You've turned it into everything I didn't want.
我的整个足球生涯 现在都看我要如何回应
My career now, all of it, will be about how well or badly
来自球迷 队友和媒体的种种压力
I take shit from the terraces, and shit from my team-mates, and shit from the press.
以后也不会再有赞助商找我了
And sponsors? Forget it.
让我来告诉你通常我都是怎么为当事人辩护的 真相就摆在你我之间
I'll tell you what normally happens between me and a client. The truth, sits between us in the middle of the table,
我却总是绕着真相东拉西扯 尽量对事实避而不谈
and I talk around it and take a great deal of care not to touch it.
随后当事人也学会跟我一样不谈及真相
And the client soon understands how to do the same thing because
因为说白了 判决结果如何跟真相没有半毛钱关系
by and large, the truth has nothing to do with the system, with all this.
但有时候 非常偶尔的 我会让事实说话
But sometimes, very occasionally, I can make room.
我可以保持沉默很久 久到足够让当事人不得不
I can shut the fuck up for long enough to let the client pick up the truth
向我坦白真相 当然前提是他想说实话 Stuart
and dump it in my lap. If the client wants to, Stuart.
一个足够长的沉默 请你说出事实 Stuart
A long enough silence. An invitation, Stuart.
到底要不要走上证人席作证 你得在明天上午之前做出决定
You don't have to go into the box, but you do need to decide by the morning.
- 你下庭多久了？ - 嗯？
- How long have you been finished? - Hm?
- 有一会儿了 - 那你还不回家？
- A while. - And you're not home yet?
- 我担心... - Morag 好吧
- I'm worried about... - Morag. Right.
我先走了 Rose 再见
I'm off, Rose. See you.
因为我担心的是Daniel
I'm worried about Daniel.
♪ A boojie boo de doo
♪ A la-ba doh de doh
♪ Koo pah ah
♪ A dooka-dook doo-dook dah ma
♪ Jinky balaaa
♪ Docky dinky doo
♪ Acka bam ja-ja choo-choo ah-ah
♪ Oooh ah ah ah ah
♪ Ah ah-ah, ah-ah ah-ah ah ah
Cross女士 问题是
The truth is, Miss Cross...
在没有路灯照明的情况下 人们很难在夜晚看清东西
...you couldn't see very well at all in the dark, with no street lighting.
没错
That's right.
所以你对Stone先生的指认 其实并不可信
And so your identification of Mr Stone as the man who assaulted you is unreliable.
以前不是这样的
It used to be different.
- 在查珀尔敦方案出台之前 - 什么方案？
- Before the Chapeltown scheme. - Scheme?
警察会搜捕沿街招妓的人
The police pick up kerb-crawlers.
抓到之后让他们选择是接受教训还是吃官司
They give 'em a choice - education or prosecution.
当然他们都会选择接受教训 男人真可悲
Of course, they all choose education. They're sad, men.
所以我们只能同危险的顾客去那些警察看不见的暗处
We're forced to go with dangerous punters in dark places where the police won't see.
这样一来皆大欢喜
Everyone's happy.
男人泄完欲回到老婆身边 老百姓看不到有伤风化的东西
Sad men go back to their wives. The residents don't have the eyesore.
警察也会因为办事卓有成效而受到嘉奖
And the police are praised for their enlightened approach.
我却在黑灯瞎火的地方被操还被打了
And I get smacked to fuck in a dark alley.
- 对此你很不满 - 当然 非常不满
- And you're angry about it. - Yes, very!
正因如此 你才会指认Stone先生
Which is why you picked out Mr Stone in the ID parade,
即使殴打你的人根本不是他
even though it wasn't him who assaulted you.
- 而且还因为你认识他 - 什么？
- That, and because you know him. - What?
- 他是你的常客 - 不是的
- He's a regular of yours. - No.
- 他说他是 - 他真敢扯
- He says he is. - Does he?
你只要随便挑一个惠顾过你的人就行
Any customer will do.
你太气愤了 以至于到底是不是他做的已经不重要了
You're so angry, it doesn't matter if he did it or not.
- 我买了一条赛狗 - 叫什么？
- I bought a greyhound for racing. - What's it called?
- 超泥马快 - 它叫什么名字？
- Fast as fuck. - What's it called?
- 超泥马快啊 - 我问名字
- Fast As Fuck. - What's it called?
- 滚蛋 - 好名字 滚蛋 真是好名字
- Sod off. - Good name. Sod Off. Really good name.
粉红色信封 紫色的字
Pink envelope, purple ink.
还喷了雅顿香水
If That Were You by Elizabeth Arden.
用的是花体字 还在Mitford的名字上画了一个桃心
A bit loopy handwriting with a heart above "I" in Mitford.
你背着Mitford在搞些什么 先生？
Is there anything we should know, sir, about Mr M?
给我吧 他都三十好几了 该找女朋友了
I'll take those. He's past 30. He needs a girlfriend.
我们这是在全约克郡为他寻觅最合适的另一半
We're doing it for him with the classiest lonely hearts in Yorkshire.
- 她 - 她
- She's... - She's...
- 非常 - 非常
- ...very... - ...very...
- 苏格兰 - 是的
- ...Scottish. - Yeah.
苏格兰 这还差不多
Scottish. That's the word.
法官总是会在众人的吹捧下高估自己的能力
The thing about being a judge is you get an inflated idea of your comic powers.
当法官在法庭上讲了一个笑话时
People laugh - jurors and so on -
人们会笑并不是因为笑话本身好笑 而是因为他们觉得出乎意料
because it's surprising when a judge tells a joke, not because it's funny.
当我回到家 想跟妻子开个玩笑时
You see, you go home... and your wife doesn't laugh...
她却不会笑
...when you try to be funny.
一个巴掌拍不响
It's a lonely business.
刚那是我们这个案子的其中一位陪审员
That's one of our jurors.
- 不该让他看到我们在聊天的 - 没关系
- We shouldn't be seen talking. - It's all right.
我脱掉法官袍之后谁都认不出来
They never recognise me without all my glad-rags on.
我时候甚至我自己都不知道我是谁
Sometimes I don't even recognise myself without my glad-rags on.
说到法官袍
Talking of glad-rags,
- Wendy de Souza打算申请皇家律师 - 是吗
- Wendy de Souza's applying for silk. - Is she?
- 你倒是可以为她做推荐人 - 为什么
- You can give her a reference. - Why?
你是这里最棒的法官 你说的话份量很足
Well, you're the nicest judge in town. What you say matters.
- 我再问你一遍 - 问我为什么总看窗户？
- I'm going to ask you again. - About looking out of windows?
问你有什么丑闻
About skeletons.
- 我没有坦白 - 是的
- I didn't tell the truth. - No.
- 我说谎了 - 对
- I lied to you. - Yeah.
- 你怎么知道 - 因为我了解你
- How did you know? - Because I know you.
- 抱歉 - 没事
- Sorry. - It's OK.
- 我是指关于丑闻 - 不 你不是指丑闻
- I meant about the skeletons. - No, you didn't.
好吧 我不是指丑闻
No, I didn't.
"慈悲不是出于勉强"
"The quality of mercy is not strained.
"它是像甘露一样从天上降下尘世"
It droppeth as the gentle rain from heaven upon the place beneath.
莎士比亚 - 威尼斯商人
"它不但给幸福于受施的人 也同样给幸福于施与的人"
It is twice blessed. It blesseth him that gives and him that takes."
我的当事人在公园中暴露自己雨衣下的"肉"
The pound of flesh exposed by my client under his raincoat in the park
"pound of flesh"，出自《威尼斯商人》，字面意思是一磅肉
引申为合法却不合理的无情要求
同威尼斯商人中夏洛克的无理要求是两回事
is not the same pound of flesh that Shylock is after.
然而 各位陪审员
But, members of the jury...
然而
But...
然而 然后呢 又忘了
But... what... Bloody hell!
- 该死 - 你好 Tom
- Bloody hell! - Hi, Tom.
我在练辩护词
I was just... practising.
- 你没事吧 - 嗯
- You OK? - Mm.
呃 那你坐一会儿呗
Er... would you like to sit down?
我刚下班 原本打算
Oh, I just finished my shift and I thought I'd erm...
- 你看见Alex了么？ - 他没回事务所？
- Well, have you seen Alex? - He's not back in chambers yet?
他可能在... 我不该这么想 抱歉 当我没说
He's probably erm... Look, this is silly. Forget it. Sorry.
可能在干什么
Probably what?
- 可能跟那个事务律师一起 - Stevie Goode？
- That solicitor. - Stevie Goode?
对 我觉得他俩有点不对劲
Yeah, I can tell there's erm... something.
我肯定他俩没事的 Alex一向爱跟别人打情骂悄 眉来眼去的
I'm sure it's nothing. Alex just flirts. It's one of his things. His... twinkle.
眉来眼去 你就帮他打马虎眼
"His twinkle." Sounds like a social worker's euphemism.
别用那种眼神看我 我又没说错 这个词挺搞笑的
Don't look at me like that. That's not fair. "Twinkle" is a funny word.
真的 我保证他俩没事
Really, I'm sure it's nothing.
我知道 抱歉
I know. I'm sorry.
好啊 抱歉？ 什么抱歉？
Hi. "Sorry"? Sorry what?
Tom的爸爸身体不太好 我很担心
Sorry about... Tom's dad. He's not very well.
他爸不是死了吗
He's dead, isn't he?
能跟你谈一下吗 Alex
Can I have a word, Alex?
- 你好 Helen - 你好
- Hi, Helen. - Hi.
"亲爱的Tom 我是个活泼的女生" 活泼还拼错了 "还很风趣 哈哈"
"Dear Tom, I'm pert... " P-U-R-T. "... and funny, ha ha.
"你可以打我的屁屁 署名Bernice"
You can slap my sides. Bernice."
还有一个 "亲爱的Tom 我是一位集美貌、才能、智慧于一身的优质女 Francesca"
Or, "Dear Tom, I'm gorgeous, talented and clever and a class above this. Francesca."
选哪个？
Which?
- 当然是Francesca - 那就是她了
- Francesca, obviously. - Francesca it is.
我假装是Tom打给她 约她明晚在酒吧见面
I'll give her a call, pretend to be Tom, invite her to the bar tomorrow night.
到时候大家都去围观Tom跟美才智的真情一刻
We can all come watch our Thomas fall in love with GTC.
- 美才智？ - 美貌 才能 智慧
- GTC? - Gorgeous, talented, clever.
- 你们明天不是都要去我家吗 那怎么... - 好吧
- You're all round at ours tomorrow night, so... - Fine.
我只是觉得Tom第一次约会 我们都在不太好
Tom should have his first date without his entire family watching.
我要她能跑 会抱
She has to be able to run, she has to be able to cuddle
还得会说英语
and she has to be able to speak English.
你们到底有没有满足以上三个要求的保姆
Now, have you got someone who can do all three?
行 今晚就让她过去
Great. Send her round tonight.
说说我自己？ 嗯 我有点腼腆
A bit about myself? Well, I'm... I'm a bit shy.
是的
Yes.
哦 好的 Fran 我能叫你Fran吗
Oh, all right, then, Fran. Can I call you Fran?
说的对 你得知道怎么认得出我
You're right. You'll need to know how to spot me.
我皮肤偏黑 很帅气 中等身材
Well, I'm dark, handsome, medium build...
脚很大 给人感觉有点像汤姆克鲁斯和阿尔帕西诺
...great feet, little bit of the Tom Cruise about me, dash of Pacino.
我会穿着蓝色山羊皮的皮鞋
And I'll be wearing blue suede shoes.
- Billy - Marlowe
- Billy. - Marlowe.
- 你好吗？ - 你想怎样？
- How are you? - What d'you want?
- 你的审讯期就在眼前了啊 - 请你滚开 行吗 Marlowe
- Trial looming. - Piss off, will you, Marlowe?
我倒是有个提议
I've got a proposal to make.
我的律师Wilson 他鼻子还没好呢 人人都说你那一拳打得好
My boy Wilson. His nose still hurts. It were a good punch, by all accounts.
只要我让他撤销对你的起诉 他就会听我的 我可能会哦
But he'd drop it against you if I told him to. And I might.
- 前提呢？ - 前提是你再回到我的事务所
- If? - If you came and played for me again.
- 什么？ - 我把大案子都给你
- What? - I could get you such heavy work.
- 开什么玩笑 - 我说真的
- Are you joking? - Completely serious.
如果我是你 肯定笑不出来
I wouldn't be laughing if I were you.
要是再这么跟我耗下去 你的律师生涯就走到头了
Go down for this and it's the end of the bar for Billy boy.
我拒绝你的提议
The answer's no.
今晚我会打电话去你家 到时候你再给我回复
I'll call you at home tonight, check you mean that.
别打 我不会同意的
Don't call me. The answer's no.
别担心 Billy
Easy, Billy.
- 混蛋 你这个混蛋 - 你会喜欢的 其实你挺开心的 真的
- You bastard. You bastard. - You love it. You're delighted, really.
- 刚来还是要走 Billy？ - 呃 要走
- Coming or going, Billy? - Er... going.
- 怎么样？ - 什么怎么样？
- And? - "And?"
- 少来 - 什么少来？
- Shut up. - "Shut up"?
少来沉默那一招
Shut up with the shutting up.
- 你指案子 - 我指案子
- The case. - The case.
不太乐观 也好也不好 陪审团恐同 我把当事人惹毛了 Stevie也生气了
Badly actually. Brilliantly and badly. Homophobic jury, pissed-off client and pissed-off Stevie,
- 就是因为我太能说 - 他是同志吗？
- all because I'm being brilliant. - Is he queer?
- 是 - 他自己说的？
- Yes. - He told you?
差不多算是吧
As good as.
- 你要输了？ - 嗯 没有
- You gonna lose? - Erm, no.
是的
Yes.
- 打算输得低调？ - 对 低调点
- Are you losing quietly? - Erm, yes. Quietly.
- 出手吧 - 出什么？
- Play it. - Play what?
- 打同志牌 - 我们不能那么做
- The queer card. - We can't do that.
我们？ 什么"我们"？ 对我来说"我们"就是事务所
"We?" What "we"? The only "we" I'm thinking about is us.
就是我们大家 我们刚成立不久 Alex 初来乍到
Us we. Chambers. We're new, Alex. We're very new.
我们急需一块跳板 现在这个案子就是跳板
We need a lift-off. This is it - this case.
我要它上全英国所有报纸的头版头条 想想我们 Alex
I want it on the front page of every rag in the country. Us, Alex.
你责无旁贷
Us is your duty.
出手吧 打同志牌 就算要输 也要搞得沸沸扬扬
Play it. Play the queer card. And if you're gonna lose, lose with a lot of noise.
- 你是哪里人？ - 冰岛
- Where are you from? - Iceland.
- 雷克雅末克？[冰岛首都] - 什么？
- Reykjavik? - What?
雷克雅末克吗？
Reykjavik?
- 你是雷克雅末克的吗？ - 不是 不过
- Are you from... "Reykjaavik"? - No. But...
- 不过？ - 我喜欢吃鳕鱼
- But...? - I love cod.
哦 那没事 我也信天主教
Oh, that's OK. I was brought up a Catholic.
她说的是"鳕鱼" 不是"上帝"
She said "cod", Billy, not "God".
她很热情 又有爱心 Daniel也喜欢她
She's warm. Affectionate. Daniel likes her.
- 而且不胖 - 什么？
- Not fat. - What?
- 身姿曼妙 - 说什么呢
- Lithe. - What?
- 就是她了 - 对
- We've found our nanny. - Yeah.
- 我也挺曼妙的 - 相当曼妙
- I'm very lithe. - You are very lithe.
- 滚一发 - 什么？
- Sex. - Sorry?
滚床单 拜托 Billy 现在
Sex, please, Billy. Now.
来吧
Come on, then.
喂
Hello?
Peter 不不 她挺好的
Peter. No, no, she's great.
不 不是雷克雅末克的
No, not Reykjavik.
那个 多谢你了 帮我们找中介
Look, thanks for... you know, Nanny Loves You.
现在干嘛？ 呃 滚床单
Right now? Er... having sex.
不是 跟Rose
No. With Rose.
- 挂了 Peter - 哦
- Bye, Peter. - Oh...!
抱歉
Sorry!
别接
Leave it.
我人生中有两件事情最重要
They're the two strongest things in my life.
- 足球和 - 身为同志
- My football and... - Being gay.
这两件事一度是互不相关的
They've been separate up to a point.
球迷们都不知道 而且媒体也没有抓到过把柄
I mean none of the fans know and the press have never got hold of it.
更衣室那些笑话只是... 他们也并不知道 只是有所察觉而已
And the dressing-room stuff was... They didn't know. They just smelt it.
- 不奇怪 - 足球跟我的同志秘密是不相关的
- Like they do. - My football and my secret are separate.
那样的一个进球得分 对我来太圆满了
Suddenly, scoring that goal in that way, it was a kind of... perfection.
我被那个进球冲昏了头 好像时间都为我静止了
The goal was so good it sort of stopped time.
- 你感觉没有什么不可以 - 我想大胆一搏
- And anything felt possible. - I wanted to make the leap.
有那么一瞬间 我愚蠢的以为这么做没关系
For one foolish moment, I thought... felt it would be all right.
把足球和你的秘密同时呈现给出来
To bring together your football and your secret.
既然我都坦白了 是不是我得认罪了
I'll have to plead guilty, won't I, now I've told you?
有些事情我可以当作没听到 身为律师我理应打破常规 掌握大局
I can be a bit deaf sometimes. It's my job to see the whole picture, beyond the rules.
如果你现在放弃 那么你今后的职业生涯将会浑浑噩噩
If you put your hands up now, you'll be living the rest of your career in a half light,
球迷的奚落嘲笑 队友的窃窃私语
taunted on the terraces, whispered about amongst your fellow pros...
你想说什么？
What are you saying?
你依然可以选择走上证人席 向人们坦白你的身份
You can still go into the witness box and tell them who you are.
就算输 也要输的有勇气有尊严
If you're gonna lose this case, lose with dignity and courage.
做个坚强的人
Be braver than the rest of us.
呃 法官大人 我有个法律问题
Er... a point of law, Your Honour.
我想请求陪审团离席以便讨论
I'm afraid we'll have to discuss it in the jury's absence.
其中一位陪审员穿的是我方当事人的客场球服
One of the jury is wearing the away-kit of my client's team.
恐怕他的决定会有失公允
I'm afraid it may indicate bias on his part.
Hay先生？
Mr Hay?
如果他是球队的支持者 他可能会偏袒Pound先生
If he is a supporter, then he may be biased in favour of Mr Pound,
如果不是 他则有可能会对当事人所涉嫌的行为产生厌恶
on the other hand, he may hate him for what he's alleged to have done.
那我们问问他好了
Well, we better ask him.
你穿着这身衣服 是否想对本庭或者庭上的任何人
Do you intend to communicate anything to this court or anyone in it
- 传达什么意思吗？ - 是的
- by wearing the shirt you have on? - Yeah.
是什么？
What?
这衣服花了我九块九毛九 这简直让我蒙羞
This cost me £9.99. It's a disgrace.
我一直全心全意的爱着这只球队 但他们拿什么回报我的爱？
I love this club with all my heart and how do they return that love?
就通过白白赚了我九块九毛九
By taking ?9.99 out of my pocket.
这我看来 这是憎恶 他们憎恶我付出的爱
In my book, that's hate. They hate me for the love I give 'em.
我不能接受 这让我不爽 我说完了
And I can't deal with it. It's causing me turmoil and... That's it.
- 爱与恨之间 - 只有一念之差
- It's a thin line. - Between love and hate.
歌曲"Thin Line Between Love and Hate"，纽约歌唱团体The Persuaders 1971年冠军单曲。
曾被多次翻唱，其中有摇滚乐队The Pretenders收录在1984年专辑《Learning to Crawl》中。
- 那个版本最好听 Hay先生？ - The Persuaders
- Best version, Mr Hay? - The Persuaders.
我觉得Pretenders的最好听 Bird先生你怎么看？
Pretenders for me. Mr Bird?
我好像不太明白法官大人您在说些什么
I'm afraid I haven't the faintest idea what Your Honour is talking about.
- 你同Cross小姐发生过性关系 - 是的
- You had sex with Miss Cross? - Yes, I did.
而且你付钱了
And you paid her?
- 我可以杀了她的 - 什么？
- I could have killed her. - What?
我把她按到墙上 然后一直打她
I shoved her up against the wall and started smacking her and smacking her.
Stone先生 我们来这不是为了讨论...
Mr Stone, this is not what we...
当时那么暗 我可以一直打下去
It was so dark, I could have carried on smacking her and smacking her.
不会有人看到的
And no-one would have come.
问题就在这里 我原本可以对这婊子为所欲为的
That's what's so brilliant. I could have done what I wanted to that stupid whore.
多棒啊 在黑暗中抽打她
Fantastic, smacking her in the dark.
Black小姐 还有问题吗？
Yes, Miss Black?
没 没有问题了
No... No more questions.
- Stone先生 - Stone先生 请你谈一谈
- Mr Stone. - Mr Stone, a word, please.
- 什么情况？ 你刚才那是什么意思？ - 我去厕所
- What's going on? What are you doing? - I'm going for a pee.
Stone先生 他可是经验丰富的社会活动家
Seasoned campaigner, Mr Stone.
什么 我就知道
What? I knew it.
混蛋！
Bastard!
你个混蛋 居然利用我在庭上公然作秀
You're using me, you bastard. This is a publicity stunt.
就是因为她在庭上提到的那个查珀尔敦方案
It's what she was talking about in court, the Chapeltown scheme.
你们两个合起来演的这一出 是不是
It's both of you, isn't it?
我做得对 不是吗 你也知道
But I'm right, aren't I? And you know I am.
她需要帮助 我就帮她一把
She needs help. I'm giving it.
我该拿他怎么办 不管怎么说他还是我的当事人
What am I gonna do? He's still my client.
你那位美丽聪慧的导师此刻正在更衣室呢
You have a lovely and supremely wise pupil-mistress and she's in the robing room right now.
如果我把事情告诉法官 她会怎么做？
If I go to the judge and tell her, what will she do?
以妨碍司法公正的罪名逮捕他们两个
Have the pair of them arrested for perverting the course of justice.
- 法官是谁？ - Styles
- Who's the judge? - Styles.
她为人公平 公正 又仁慈
A profoundly fair, just and humane human being.
我觉得自己太蠢了
It's made me feel... really foolish.
- 还很气愤 - 对 气愤
- And angry. - And angry.
换作是你会怎么做？
What would you do?
身为律师并不意味着就要失去自我
We don't have to stop being ourselves just because we wear silly clothes.
给
Here.
他愚弄了你我 和其他所有人
He's made us all look like idiots. Me, you...
- 还亵渎了法律 - 是的 法律
- The law. - Yes. The law.
如果要你说 你会建议我逮捕他们
And if you were able to say it, you'd suggest I have him arrested.
低调进行 不能让媒体知道
Quietly. So the press don't see.
你是Rose Fitzgerald的实习生 对吧
You're Rose Fitzgerald's pupil, aren't you?
她当年是我的实习生 希望她能把从我这里学到的都传授给你
She was my pupil. Hope she's passing on everything I taught her.
她说您为人公平 公正 而且仁慈
She says you're a profoundly fair, just and humane human being.
到哪总是有美女相伴 算是身为足球明星的生活特色？
The glamorous lifestyle of footballers. Always a girl on the arm?
是的
Yeah.
进球的时候 你是什么感觉
Tell us how you felt when that goal went in.
感觉很棒
Great.
只是很棒？
"Great"?
但是
And...
什么？
Yes?
- 百感交集 - 为什么？
- Complicated. - Because?
我很高兴
I was happy.
因为那样的一记进球 是对自己身份的一种表达
When you score a goal like that, it's a very full expression of...
作为足球运动员？
Who you are? As a footballer?
是的 意义重大
Yeah. It has real meaning.
那么对Biggs的吻呢？ 有什么意义吗？
What about kissing Biggs? What did that mean?
- 这也是一种表达 - 表达什么？
- It was an expression. - Of?
讽刺吗？
Irony?
- 不是 - 那是什么？
- No. - Then what?
对我本质的表达
Of who I am.
你本质是什么？
Which is?
同志足球运动员
A gay footballer.
- 你看起来有点不一样 - 是吗
- You look different. - Do I?
律师这个行业能更快的改变一个人
The bar speeds up change in people.
你看起来 没有刚才那么害怕 也没那么苏格兰了
You look... a little less scared and a lot less Scottish.
- 谢谢 - 口红也很好看
- Thanks. - And your lipstick is... a good thing.
Stuart Pound有罪
Stuart Pound is guilty.
根据法律 他确实犯下了猥亵罪
As the law stands, he's committed an indecent assault.
他对此并不否认
He admits it.
法官大人也会建议各位评审员履行你们的义务 给出有罪判决
And soon you'll be told by His Honour, the judge, that it's your duty to find him guilty.
你们一定在想 那我还在这里费什么口舌
Which may make you wonder why I'm talking to you now.
下面我来解释
I'll tell you.
小时候 我曾在埃兰路球场的看台上
As a boy, I stood on the terraces at Elland Road
目睹过天才球星Albert Johanneson的风采
and I watched a very gifted footballer, Albert Johanneson, play.
他已经去世了 最后的那段日子里 他酗酒 肥胖 事业无成
He's dead now. He died an alcoholic. Overweight. Washed up.
为什么会这样？
And do you know why he ended up like that?
因为每当他上球场踢比赛的时候 人们都会辱骂他是黑人
Because every time he played a game of football, he was abused because he was black.
没有人会在意他的球技 他的风趣 他正派的人品
And no-one cared that he was hugely talented and funny and decent.
人们鄙视他 仅仅因为他是黑人
He was black and he was despised for it.
当然了 如今的人们已经不会再带着种族歧视的有色眼镜对待足球了
Now, football's getting better and better at dealing with racism.
但是Albert Johanneson当时却为此付出了代价
But Albert Johanneson paid the price.
他只是曾经受过迫害的众人之一 而他没有撑下去
He was one of the first. And he didn't make it.
我想请你们大家做件事
I want you to do something, all of you.
请你们转过去看着Stuart Pound
I want you to turn and look at Stuart Pound.
眼光请不要移开
I want you to keep looking at him.
然后请每个人说
And I want you to say, all of you,
"虽然按照法律规定 你确实是犯下了此罪"
"You may be guilty of this offence under the law...
"但我们绝不会看不起你"
...but we do not despise you.
"你向人们展现了真实的自己 我们不会像四万球迷那样侮辱你"
We do not join with the 40,000 in abusing you when you show us who you are.
"基佬"
Queer...
"娘炮"
...ponce...
"玻璃 我们不会用这种词形容你"
...nonce... are words we do not want."
等你们说完后
Do this.
请回到仲裁室 诚如各位必须的那样 给出有罪判决
And then go back into your jury room and find him guilty, as you must.
但离席之前
But let him know...
请告诉他
...before you go...
他这么做并没有错
...that he's an innocent man.
有件事想请你帮忙 法官大人
There's something I'd like you to do for me, Judge.
- 你说 - Wendy de Souza皇家律师的申请
- I'm listening. - Wendy de Souza's silk application.
- 想请您写一封推荐信 - 我不能写
- I'd be grateful for a reference. - I can't do that.
- 你确定？ - 她不让我写
- Are you sure about that? - She asked me not to.
那也请你写
Do it anyway.
- 我得尊重她的请求 - 是吗？ 您夫人最近怎么样？
- I have to honour her request. - Really? How's your wife?
- 你到底想说什么？ - 咱们别把什么都说破
- What are you trying to say, exactly? - Let's not do exactly.
就体会字里行间的言外之意吧 我喜欢凡事尽量开化
Let's read between the lines and not do exactly. I'm all in favour of civilised behaviour.
- Stevie - 嘘
- Stevie. - Shh.
你这个样子 在密西西比会被捕的
You could be arrested... in Mississippi.
什么？
What?
那里出台了一个新条例
There's a new law.
即使穿着衣服 在公共场合勃起也是违法的
It's illegal to stand to attention in a public place, even with clothes on.
她挺好的
She's great!
这不太像Tom的作风啊 第一次约会就把她带出来跟朋友见面
A bit peculiar of Tom. First date - supper with all his friends.
是不该带她来 我想他可能还没准备好跟她单独相处吧
Wasn't supposed to bring her here. I guess he's not ready for one-to-one. Not yet.
会有那么一天的 我们做了件好事
But he'll get there. It's a good thing we've done.
Billy
Billy!
好了 菜马上就齐
OK. I'm nearly ready here.
- Alex呢？ - 他说了要来的
- Where's Alex? - He said he'd be here.
干得好
Good boy.
嗨
Hi.
- 嗨 - 嗨 你去哪了
- Hi. - Hi. Where have you been?
- 什么？ - 跟我一起 聊了会儿天
- What? - With me. Shooting the breeze.
你们知道吗 密西西比有一条新的法律 禁止在公共场合勃起
Do you know in Mississippi, there's a new law against having an erection in a public place.
- 真的？ - 真的
- Straight up? - Straight up.
只要高于金泰尔半岛 你就倒霉了
More upwards than the Mull of Kintyre and you're nicked.
- 真的要因为勃起蹲牢？ - 他们指的是金泰尔在地图上的仰角
- Banged up for having a boner? - It's the angle of the Mull of Kintyre.
他回头会给你展示 Francesca
He can show you later, Francesca.
我来吧
I'll go.
Mull of Kintyre，金泰尔半岛，苏格兰地名。
金泰尔准则"Mull of Kintyre test/rule"也被英国电影分级委员会
作为判定男性生殖器能否在画面中出现的非正式标准
详情请参见英文维基"Mull of Kintyre test"词条，有图有真相
♪ ... the plpes are calllng From glen to glen
♪ And down the mountalnslde
♪ The summer's gone
♪ And all the roses falllng
♪ 'Tls you, 'tls you
♪ Must go and I must blde
♪ But come ye back
♪ When summer's in the meadow
♪ Or when the valley's hushed
♪ And whlte wlth snow
♪ It's I'll be here
♪ In summer or in shadow
♪ Oh, Danny boy
♪ I love you so
- 我以前经常唱的 - 唱给Rory听？
- I used to sing that a lot. - To Rory?
- 是啊 - 现在呢？
- Yeah. - And now?
对了 我要做Dan的教父
By the way. Dan. I'm his godfather.
- 真的？ - 错不了
- Are you? - You bet your life I am.
我诚实守信
Loyal. Trusting.
之类之类的
That kind of thing.
- 我去告诉Rose - 是该告诉她
- I'll tell Rose. - We should tell Rose.
去告诉她吧
Let's tell Rose.
- 她会高兴坏的 - 肯定欣喜若狂
- She'll be thrilled. - She'll be over the moon.